The scrollbar allows users to select a numeric value
Scrollbar ではユーザーがハンドルをドラッグすることで
from 0 to 1 by dragging the handle of the scrollbar.
0 から 1 の範囲で数値を指定できます
Scrollbars are usually used to set or change a value
Scrollbar は一般的に 別の UI 要素や
on another UI element or component.
コンポーネントの数値を設定または変更する用途で使われます
Scrollbars are commonly used with a scroll rect,
通常は Scroll Rect と組み合わせて使われます
which can hold and mask contents
この Scroll Rect はコンテンツを格納し
too large to be easily viewed.
表示には大きすぎるコンテンツにマスクをかけるものです
The scroll rect will use the value from the
Scroll Rect は Scrollbar から受け取った値を使用し
scrollbar to control how it's contents are scrolled.
コンテンツのスクロール制御を行います
For more information on scroll rects
Scroll Rect の詳細については
please see the information linked below.
下記リンク先の情報を参照してください
The scrollbar's value is set by the position of
Scrollbar の値はハンドルの全体長における
the handle along the length of the scrollbar.
現在位置で指定されます
The value is a normalised value that starts at
値には正規化された値が使われ
0 at one end of the scrollbar
一方の端が 0 から始まり
and increases up to 1 at the other end.
反対の端で最大 1 まで増加します
A value of 0.5 indicates the halfway point.
0.5 はちょうど中間点です
To create a new scrollbar use the Create
スクロールバーを新規作成するには Create メニューから
menu to Create - UI - Scrollbar.
Create > UI > Scrollbar を選択します
like all UI elements, the scrollbar element
Scrollbar 要素も他の UI 要素と同様に
must be the child of a canvas.
Canvas の子にする必要があります
If one is not present when creating a pre-made
既存スクロールバーの作成時に Canvas が存在しない場合は
scrollbar a new canvas will be created.
新たに Canvas が作成されます
For more information on the canvas
Canvas の詳細については
please see the information linked below.
下記リンク先の情報を参照してください
When the scrollbar is created it is made from a
Scrollbar の作成時にはゲームオブジェクトの
family of game objects.
ファミリーがまとめて作成されます
The children are the rect transform and image components
子は RectTransform と Image コンポーネントで
that define the sliding area and the handle graphic.
それぞれスライド領域とハンドルのグラフィックを定義します
The parent game object is where the required
親ゲームオブジェクトには Scrollbar の
scrollbar script resides.
必須スクリプトが置かれます
The background image is a component on the parent game object.
また背景画像となる Image コンポーネントも親ゲームオブジェクトに配置されます
Interact-able determines whether or not this particular
Interactable（インタラクティブ性）チェックボックスは
scrollbar will accept input.
このスクロールバーが入力を受け付けるか否かを指定します
To prevent interaction with a scrollbar
スクロールバーを表示のみでユーザーに操作させない場合は
set Interact-able to false.
Interactable をオフにしておきます
When interact-able is set to false
Interactable がオフの場合
the transition state for the scrollbar element
transition（遷移）の状態が自動的に
will be set to the disabled state.
Disabled（無効）に変更されます
By default the scrollbar element will display
Scrollbar 要素はデフォルトでは
the normal state of the scrollbar.
Normal（通常）状態で表示されます
Depending upon the transition mode chosen
transition モードの指定によっては
a scrollbar can also display a highlighted
これ以外に Highlighted（強調表示）
pressed and disabled state.
Pressed（押下）・Disabled（無効）状態でも表示されます
Transition Mode determines whether or not the
対象 Scrollbar 要素がこれらの状態を
scrollbar element will display any of these additional states,
表示するかどうか および各状態における
and if so controls the slider's look in each state
スクロールバーの見た目と状態間の遷移は
and the style of the transitions between the states.
transition のモードで決定されます
The transition mode property is shared
transition モードのプロパティは
by many UI elements and will be
各種 UI 要素と共通であるため
covered in it's own lesson.
独立したレッスンが設けられています
For more information on transitions and the
transition および
transition mode property please see the
transaction モードのプロパティの詳細については
information linked below.
下記リンク先の情報を参照してください
When using transitions with a scrollbar
Scrollbar 要素で transition を使用する場合は
it is worth noting that, with the exception of
animation transition 以外のケースでは
the animation transition mode,
視覚的な変化はハンドルのグラフィックにのみ
any visual changes are only seen in the handle graphic
適用され それ以外の UI 要素には
not the rest of the UI element.
適用されないので注意してください
Navigation describes how the selection
Navigation はキーボード入力や
of UI elements is handled when using
コントローラー入力使用時の
keyboard or controller input.
UI 要素の扱われ方を設定する項目です
Navigation is shared by many UI elements
Navigation は多数の UI 要素で共有されるものなので
and will be covered in it's own lesson.
独立したレッスンが設けられています
For most circumstances navigation can simply
なお 多くの場合この設定は
be set to automatic.
Automatic（自動）にして問題ありません
For more information on navigation
Navigation の詳細については
please see the information linked below.
下記リンク先の情報を参照してください
Handle rect is a reference to the rect transform
Handle Rect（ハンドル矩形）はハンドルに
on the graphic used for the handle.
使われるグラフィックの RectTransform への参照です
Direction sets both the axis and
Direction（方向）ではメーターの縦横と
the direction of the value changed.
値の増減方向を指定します
The value is a normalised value that starts with 0
値には 0 から始まる正規化された値が使われ
at one end of the scrollbar and increasing
それを一方の終端とし 反対側の端に
up to 1 at the other end.
到達すると 1 となります
For example, with the choice of left to right,
たとえば LeftToRight（左から右）を指定した場合は
the starting value of 0 will be at the left of the scrollbar
開始値の 0 はスクロールバー左端になります
and the value of the scrollbar will increase
スクロールバーの値はハンドルを
proportionally as the handle moves from left to right
左から右に移動させていくと比例的に増加します
with a value of 1 at the right.
右端が最大値の 1 です
The choices for direction are
方向として選択できるオプションは
LeftToRight,
LeftToRight（左から右）
RightToLeft,
RightToLeft（右から左）
BottomToTop and TopToBottom.
BottomToTop（下から上）そして TopToBottom（上から下）です
The value is the current value of the scrollbar
Value はスクロールバーの現在値を示します
When the value is set in the inspector during edit time
インスペクターで編集中に指定した値は
this will set the starting value for the scrollbar.
スクロールバーの初期値として設定されます
Size is the fractional size of the
Size は 0～1 で指定する値で
handle within the scrollbar,
スクロールバーの
in a range of 0 to 1.
ハンドルの大きさを示します
Number of steps is the number of distinct
Number Of Steps はスクロールバーの
positions allowed by the scrollbar.
スライダ停止位置をどう区切るかを指定します
For a smooth continuous scroll
なめらかにスクロールさせるには
set this value to 0 or 1.
値を 0 または 1 に指定してください
The UI framework contains a powerful events system
UI フレームワークが持つ強力なイベントシステムは
This is created when the canvas is created.
Canvas 作成時に自動的に作成されます
When the event system detects a click
このイベントシステムが スクロールバー要素の
or a drag on the scrollbar
クリック操作またはドラッグ操作を検出すると
the event system will call an OnValueChanged event.
OnValueChanged イベントが呼び出されます
The scrollbar component includes a built-in
scrollbar コンポーネントにはビルトインの
on value changed function list
On Value Changed 関数リストがあります
that contains a list of all the functions
このリスト中の関数はすべて
that are called when the scroll values change.
スクロールバーの値が変化した時に呼び出されます
Additional events can be detected and used
検出するイベントを追加して
by the scrollbar element ,  but this requires
Scrollbar 要素で使用することもできますが
an additional component.
その場合は追加でコンポーネントをアタッチする必要があります
For more information on how to use the build in
ビルトイン関数リスト / イベント / イベントシステムおよび
function's list, events, the event system and event triggers
イベントトリガーの使い方詳細については
please see the information linked below.
下記リンク先の情報を参照してください
In most cases the scrollbar will
通常 Scrollbar は
be used with the scroll rect.
Scroll Rect と組み合わせて使います
which will automatically use the dynamic
Scroll Rect を関連付けておくと
value of the scrollbar when they are associated.
スクロールバーの値が動的に使用されるようになります
For more information on the scroll rect
Scroll Rect の詳細については
please see the information linked below.
下記リンク先の情報を参照してください